A bizarre story of love.
Obsession is a thriller, mystery, drama film directed by Brian De Palma.
A wealthy New Orleans businessman becomes obsessed with a
young woman who resembles his late wife.
Michael Courtland, played by Cliff Robertson.
Elizabeth Courtland / Sandra Portinari, played by Geneviève Bujold.
Robert Lasalle, played by John Lithgow.
Maid, played by Sylvia Kuumba Williams.
Amy Courtland, played by Wanda Blackman.
Third Kidnapper, played by J. Patrick McNamara.
Obsession is a 1976 American neo-noir psychological thriller film directed by Brian De
Palma, starring Cliff Robertson, Geneviève Bujold, and John Lithgow.
The screenplay was written by Paul Schrader, from
a story by De Palma and Schrader.
Bernard Herrmann provided the film's soundtrack before his death in 1975.
The story is about a prominent New Orleans businessman who is haunted by guilt following the
death of his wife and daughter during a kidnapping-rescue attempt gone wrong.
Years later, he meets and falls in love with a young woman who
is the exact look-alike of his long dead wife.
Both De Palma and Schrader have pointed to Alfred Hitchcock's Vertigo (1958) as the
major inspiration for Obsession's narrative and thematic concerns.
Schrader's script  was extensively rewritten and pared down by De Palma before shooting, causing the
screenwriter to proclaim a complete lack of interest in the film's subsequent production and release.
Completed in 1975, Columbia Pictures picked up the distribution rights but demanded that
minor changes be made to reduce potentially controversial aspects of the plot.
When finally released in the late summer of 1976, it became De Palma's first
substantial box-office success and received mixed reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of sense of guilt, ransom, money
delivery, fake identity, florence, italy.
The tone is mind_bending and emotional and intense.